Guide to the John Russell Mason papers, 1931-1981 MS0242.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
John Russell Mason papers
1931-1981
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mason, John Russell
MS0242.UA
13.5 Linear Feet
Collection consists of records, correspondence, photographs, and ephemeral materials ranging in date from 1931 to 1981. The records document John Russell Mason's librarianship education at Columbia University, individual exhibits held at the University Library, and his career at The George Washington University.
Box 13
Box 11
Box 12
Box 9
Box 10
Box 7
Box 8
Box 5
Box 6
Box 3
Box 4
Box 1
Box 2
Box 15
Box 14
Box 16
Box 17
Box 18
Box 19
Box 20
Box 21
Box 22
Box 23
Box 24
Box 25
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the University Archives by the estate of John Russell Mason.
Biographical Note
John Russell Mason (1900-1981) was associated with The George Washington University (GW) for most of his adult life, first as a student, then as the University Librarian and Curator of Art from 1933 to 1966.
Mason was born January 1, 1900 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and his family moved to Washington, D.C. when he was a young boy. He graduated from Washington's Roosevelt High School, and entered GW in 1918. Mason earned an B.A. in 1923, and an M.A. in 1925 both concentrating in English.
Mason began working in the library while an undergraduate and was appointed Chief Assistant in 1920. He was made Assistant Librarian following his gradation, a post he held until 1929. He decided to dedicate his career to librarianship, and enrolled in the Library School of Columbia University. Before finishing at Columbia in 1933, Mason was promoted at GW from Associate Librarian to the position of Chief Librarian the same year. In 1939, the Lisner Library was constructed and during Mason's service, the library holdings increased fourfold, including the purchase of the library of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace in 1950.
In 1944, he was given the added responsibly of being the Curator of Art. In that capacity he arranged 176 exhibitions of works of art which ranged from the Walter P. Chrysler Collection to the annual student shows. He was instrumental in the acquisition of two full length Gilbert Stuart portraits of George Washington, a Rembrandt Peale "porthole" portrait, and the oil portraits of presidents of the University.
An accomplished organist, Mason played at numerous universality convocations and commencements for over thirty-five years. He also played for a number of Washington churches, among them Central Presbyterian Church from 1926 to 1944 as the organist. In 1951, the University honored him with an alumni achievement award, and in 1965 he was confirmed the status of Librarian and Curator of Art Emeritus. He retired officially a year later.
He was a member of the American Library Association, the Library Association of Great Britain, the District of Columbia Library Association (serving as President from 1942 to 1944), the Special Libraries Association, the American Guild of Organists, Theta Delta Chi, the Cosmos Club, and the Arts Club of Washington. In 1974, the Friends of the Libraries dedicated the John Russell Mason Room in the University Library (named Gelman Library in 1980).
He continued his life of bachelorhood at his long residence in the Arts Club of Washington until his death. John Russell Mason died February 28, 1981 in Washington, D.C. In 1983, Mason's will provided for the establishment of a $220,000 permanent endowment for the purchase of books for the Gelman Library, known as the John Russell Mason Book Fund.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
The John Russell Mason collection consists of records, correspondence, photographs, and ephemeral materials. The materials range in date from 1931 to 1981. The collection covers records documenting his librarianship education at Columbia University, individual exhibits held at the University Library, and records he kept while in office at The George Washington University. The collection was donated to the University Archives of the Special Collections Department by the estate of John Russell Mason.
Collection Organization
Organized in six series: Columbia Library School, American Library Association, District of Columbia Library Association, Librarian and curator of art, Library exhibits under J.R. Mason as curator, and Papers, photographs, ephemera.
Collection note
Formerly ACC#242
Library science; Photographs; Art; Gelman Library; Library Administration; Gifts; Washington (D.C.); Endowments; Exhibitions; United States -- New York (N.Y.); George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; District of Columbia Library Association; Columbia University; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; American Library Association; George Washington University. Friends of the Libraries; Mason, John Russell; Marvin, Cloyd Heck; George Washington University
- Columbia Library School, 1932-1943; MS0242 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains notes, exams, syllabi, bibliographies, and other related documents. They range in date from 1932 to 1943. They reflect te curricula required at Columbia's School of Library Science.
  - S201, Bibliography, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - S117, Library Records, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - S204, Book Selection, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Summer sessions other universities, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 206, Reference, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Teachers College Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School of Library Service, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - S215, Organization and Administration, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - S105, Reference, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 202, Subject Bibliography, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 252, Subject Bibliography, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - S203, S204, Book Selection, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book Selection, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Projects, etc., undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty notices, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - English 2, Use of Libraries, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 232, History of Books and Libraries, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Association of the Columbia School for L.S., 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 206A, Government Documents, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - S211, Classification, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - S222,College and University Libraries, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 226, Special Libraries, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - S207, Cataloguing, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - S208, Cataloguing, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Columbia Library School, correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - GWU, Assistant Librarian, correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- American Library Association, 1931-1948; MS0242 Series 2; 1.5 Linear foot
  This series consists of correspondence and committee minutes. They range in date from 1931 to 1948. They concern mason's membership in the American Library Association (ALA).
  - ALA, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - ALA, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ALA, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ALA, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ALA, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ALA, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ALA, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ALA, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ALA, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ALA, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ALA, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - ALA, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ALA, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ALA, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ALA, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ALA, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ALA, Committee on Federal Relations, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ALA, Friends of Libraries, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Distric of Columbia Library Association, 1933-1948; MS0242 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence and committee minutes. They range in date from 1933 to 1948. They consists of Mason's tenure as President of District of Columbia Library Association (DCLA).
  - DCLA, President, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - DCLA (President, correspondence), 1933-1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - DCLA (President, correspondence), 1941-1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - DCLA, Publicity, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ALA for DCLA, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - DCLA, visit to the White House Library, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - DCLA, 50 books exhibit, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - DCLA lecturers, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - DCLA, correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - DCLA, correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - DCLA, correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Librarian and curator of art, 1943-1965; MS0242 Series 4; 3 Linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence, biographic information, and bibliographies. They range in date from 1943 to 1965. They concern the organizing of art exhibits at The George Washington University and the contacts with artists and institutions in the Washington D.C. area.
  - Middle Eastern Library Association and Allied Organizations, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Old library plans and improvements, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Special Libraries Association, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Inventory, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Report on the Library of the School of Musicology, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Library Committee and Library Staff Book, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Office of Strategic Services, acquisitions, 06/27/1946 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Library Committee, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Medical Library periodicals, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Middle States Report-binding, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Endowments, gifts, memorials, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Endowments, gifts, memorials, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Endowments, gifts, memorials, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Endowments, gifts, memorials, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Gifts: Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Gifts rejected, correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - James Monroe portrait, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Library correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Library correspondence, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Medical Library, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Law Library, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reserve Book Reading Room, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Periodical Room, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Reference and Circulation Departments, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cataloguing Department, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Librarian's office, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Library, general, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Victory Book Campaign, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Library changes, 05/1947 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Biographical material for Mrs. Gilbert, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Books added to the Library - weekly lists, 02/01/1948 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Curator of Art, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Curator of Art, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Curator of Art, 1951-1961 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Curator of Art, 1959-1964 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Curator of Art: George Washington portrait, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Student Assistants applications, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Trustee, High School Scholarship, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Books for Russia Campaign, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Lisner Hall Library, formal opening, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Encumbrance letters; Faculty needs, survey, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Special Libraries Association, Washington, DC Chapter, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Student Art Show (ODK Art Club), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Curator of Art Annual Report, 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Library correspondence, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Composers, Authors and Publishers, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Victory Book Campaign, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - J.R. Mason, Selective Service, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Medical Librarian's Annual Report, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - George Washington Statue by Thomas Sail, portrait by Emanuel Leutze, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Karolik collection, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - President Lloyd Elliott's appointment, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Veerhof Galleries, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hans Kindler, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Order Department Report (acquisitions), 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Art-Insurance, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Art-Insurance, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Report to the President (library), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Engineers' Council for Professional Development, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - G.W.U, Masters Thesis pre 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - William Smallwood, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Mary Howe, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - J.R. Mason, musician, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Personal correspondence: Harry Peterson, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lincoln (Howe), 02/1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - C.Gregory Stapko: Dolley Madison and John Ouincy Adams portraits; Cloyd Marvin by Augustus V. Tack, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Cloyd H. Marvin - bust and plaque, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Wendel Artistic Lighting Corp. - J.R. Mason, 05/1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hans Kindler - program Book, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hans Kindler - bust, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hans Kindler - bust unveiling, 11/02/1950 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Exhibits, 1959-60 and future, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Executive Training, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - J.R. Mason, short biography by Elmer Kayser, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Douglas H. Teller appointed Curator of Art, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Library correspondence, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - "Religion in Life Week " at G.W.U., undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Library - computers and automation, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Fox portrait by Egeli, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Library "Music Room", undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Library exhibits under J.R. Mason as curator, 1948-1966; MS0242 Series 5; 4 Linear feet
  This series consists of correspondence, programs, and lists. They range in date from 1948 to 1966. They concern the exhibits held in the University Library.
  Binders include lists and programs, for each exhibit held, which can also be used as finding aids for individual exhibit.
  - Exhibits: 1 through 45, 11/1943-09/1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits: 46 through 85, 10/1952-12/1956 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits: 86 through 133, 01/1957-05/1961 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Exhibits: 134 through 176, 06/1961-03/1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Art(#14-25), 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #1 Hellen Fowler;#2 Hugo Inden, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - #3 Navy Exhibit, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - #4 G.W.U. Presidents Exhibit, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - #5 Alice Acheson, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - #11 Edith McCartney, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - #12 The Story of the Air Conditioning, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - #13 Abbot Art School, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - #14 Garnett W. Jex, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - #15 Sidney D. Gelfand; #16 Phillip F. Bell, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - #17 Charles H. Walther, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - #18 R. McGill Mackall, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - #19(Helen) Donnel B. Young, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - #20 Alice Kindler, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - #21 Fremont Davis, 02/27-03/19/1950 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - #22 Eugen Weisz, 03/21/1950-04/14/1950 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - #23 Ilona Deak-Ebner (Ellinger), 04/16-05/05/1950 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - #24 Hedin, Lewis, Sickman, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - #25 W. Lloyd Wright - gift and 1800-1950 exhibit, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - #26 Tasev Exhibition, 12/1950 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - #27 Richard Lahey, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #28 Bertha Noyes, 02/1951 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - #29 Bruce Howe, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - #30 Dean Stambaugh; #31 Galdys Milligan, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - #32 GWU Art Club - 3rd Annual Show, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - #33 University Permanent Collection and Garnet W. Jex, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - #34 Kenneth Stubbs, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - #35 S. Burtis Baker; #36 James Monroe's House Exhibition, 11/1951 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - #37 Marjorie, Duncan and Laughlin Phillips, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - #38 Textile Museum - Caucasian Dragon Rugs and Related Embroideries, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - #39 Ruth Perkins Stafford - Portraits of Interiors Associated with President Washington, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - #40 Three Generations of Howes, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - #41 GWU Art Club - 4th Annual Show, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - #42 Alfred H. McAdams (Kline, too), undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - #43 Donald Kline (see also #42), undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - #44 American Federation of Arts - Shows Paintings by Walt Kuhn and the Associated American Artist Group, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - #45 Permanent Collection, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - #46 W. W. Corcoran Tribute, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - #47 Textile Museum - Turkish Textiles (16 &18 century), undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - #48 Augustus V. Tack from the Phillips Collection, undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - #49 Armistead Peter, 3rd, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - #50 Mt. Vernon, 02/1953 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - #51 English Watercolors, 03/1953 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - #52 GWU Art Club - 5th Annual Show, 04/1953 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - #53 Japanese Prints - Robert E. Scudder, 05/1953 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - #54 Permanent Collection, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - #55 Joseph Pennell - etchings, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - #56 Agnes Stone, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - #57 Rudolf Von Huhn, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - #58 Peruvian Textiles, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - #59 George Washington Prints - Maryland, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - #60 Ethiopian Paintings, 03/1954 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - #61 GWU Art Club - 6th Annual Show, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - #62 Rowland Lyon, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - #63 Permanent Collection, 06/1954-09/1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - #64 Watercolor - Olin Dows, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - #65 Lithographs - Benton Spruance, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - #66 Indonesian Textiles, 12/1954 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - #67 Sculpture by Jane Love, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - #63 Index of American Designs, 02/1955 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - #69 Photographs - D. Be Harport, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - #70 GWU Art Club - 7th Annual Show, 04/1955 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - #71 Maps - Richard Edes Harrison, 05/1955 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - #72 Permanent Collection - Hats by Marian Stevens, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - #74 Thomas Mather Barnett - Martha McKay Barnett, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - #75 Drawings by Eugen Weisz, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - #76 Walter K. Bachrach, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - #77 Photographs by A. Audrey Bodine, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - #78 Honoring George Washington the man, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - #79 Vincenz Ruzicka - Watercolors, pastels and drawings, 03/1956 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - #80 GWU Art Club - 8th Annual Show, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - #81 Modern Design in Ancient Art - Textile Museum, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - #82 Washington (W. Lloyd Wright), 05/1956-09/1956 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - #83 A. J. Miller, 10/1956 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - #84 Pierson Underwood; Sergeant Kendalls, 11/1956 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - #85 Julie H. Rush, 12/1956 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - #86 Ruth S. Rose, 01/1957 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - #87 Luis Crespo - Paintings, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - #89 Chrysler, 03/1957 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - #90 GWU Art Club - 9th Annual Show, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - #91 Guggenheim, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - #92 E. Hoyt, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - #93 Arthur Healy, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - #94 Kaethe Kollwitz, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - #96 Mt. Vernon, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - #97 T. Gage, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - #98 GWU Art Club - 10th Annual Art Show, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - #99 Chester Leich, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - #100 Don Callander, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - #101 Summer 1958 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - #102 UNESCO Watercolor, 09/1958-10/1958 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - #103 The Interpretive Photography of Lewis W. Hine; Footlights and Skylines - photos of the American Stage, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - #105 Caroline Duriex, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - #106 Chinese Landscape Painting, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - #107 Chester Leich, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - #108 Washingtoniana - Florence Berryman Collection, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - #109 Armistead Peter, 3rd, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - #110 GWU Art Club - 11th Annual Show, 04/1959 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - #111 American Federation of Arts - The New Landscape, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - #112 Wallendahl (Mowinckel), undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - #113 Early Washington from the W.Lloyd Wright Collection, 06/1959-09/1959 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - #114 Abdullah Ariff, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - #115 Mikola Shramchenko, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - #116 History of Photography (George Eastman House), undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Two Christmas paintings, 12/1959 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - #117 Boston Public Library - Contemporary Prints, undated (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - #118 Vincent Ruzicka - Greek Fragments, undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - #119 George Washington - the man, 9th, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - #120 Charles Smith, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - #121 Art of Mentally Retarded, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - #122 GWU Art Club - 12th Annual Show, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - #123 Outer Mongolia - Photographs by Lisa Larsen, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - #124 Joseph Pennel1 - Etchings and Lithographs, 05/1960 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - #125 Bertha Noyes - Portraits, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - #126 James R. Black, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - #127 Lahmer and Gentili, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - #128 Stephen Wrobel, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - #129 Gib Crockstt, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - #130 George Washington - the man, 10th, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - #131 Tyson - Walcott, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - #132 GWU Art Club - 13th Annual Show, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - #133 Bjorn Egeli, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - #134 Summer 1961 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - #136 Constant Le Braton, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - #137 F. A. Comstock, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - #138 Contemporary Religious Prints, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - #139 English Watercolors, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - #140 Donneson, undated (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - #141 Armistead Peter, 3rd, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - #142 GWU Art Club - 14th Annual Show, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - #143 J. R. Brevoort, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - #144 U. S. Grant, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Russell Jones and the University Collection, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - #145 MFA Theses, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - #146 Iron Curtain - Smithsonian Institution, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - #147 M. Hayward, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - #148 Dan Callander, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - #149 Italian Painters (Standard Oil Co.), undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - #150 Hugo Steiner-Prag, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - #151 George Washington, the Man and the University, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - #152 Ernest Biddle, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - #153 GWU Art Club - 15th Annual Show, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - #154 Benton Spruance, 05/1963 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - #155 Douglas Teller, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - #156 Blanche Elliot King, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - #157 Armistead Peter, 3rd, 01/1964 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - #158 Ruth Perkins Safford, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)